# Tyler La Fronz

Marlboro, NJ • +1 (732) 737-7878 • tyler@lafronz.com • TylerLaFronz.com

## **Software Developer**

Solution-focused, innovative Full Stack Software Developer with a passion for the field and experience using a wide array of technology and a bachelor's degree.

- Innovative thought leader with demonstrated experience developing and implementing processes to improve operations.
- Proficient in fostering strategic relationships with customers and co-workers to meet company goals.
- Proven success at leading cross-functional teams in a variety of settings and ensuring efficient workflows.

#### Core Technologies

Languages	Java, C/C++, Assembly Language, JavaScript
Tools and Plugins	D3, Git, Logisim, MS SQL, WireShark, Jenkins, GCP
Platforms and IDEs	Docker, OpenShift, Heroku, BigQuery, Kubernetes
Working Knowledge	Python, R, Bash, Angular, Ruby, Spring MVC, Spring Boot, Go Lang

## **Education**

**Bachelor of Science, Computer Science**, Wentworth Institute of Technology, Boston, MA (August 2017)

- Dean's List Summer 2016 & Spring 2017
- Student Government President and Academic Affairs Officer.
- Introduced Preferred Name Policy across the intranet to allow the use of name students, faculty, and staff to identify with.
- Collaborated with student leaders within the Fenway consortium entailing five additional area colleges and universities.

### Training & Development

Wentworth Leadership Academy, 12-week Leadership seminar

#### **Appointments**

- Registrar, Director of the Center for Diversity and Social Justice candidate search committees
- Wentworth Alumni Association Student Board Member

# **Professional Experience**

United Parcel Service, Inc, Parsippany, NJ, 2017 - Present

#### Intermediate Applications Developer (Jun. 2019 to Present)

Lead the team as the top DevOps Engineer. Collaborate with other teams to ensure the on-time deployment of secure web applications running in three Kubernetes clusters.

- Orchestrated cross-team deployments Google Cloud.
- Developed and implemented policies and processes for DevOps Pipeline.

Continued...

Spearheaded the inclusion of new development languages and technologies.

## Software Developer II (Nov. 2018 to Jun. 2019)

Collaborate with the product owner and management ensuring on-time delivery of features as Full-stack Web Application Developer using Spring Boot and Java.

- Cut costs by aiding in current application rework.
- Supported a subset of the team as Scrum Master.
- Designed and developed applications using BigQuery and Kubernetes.

### **Software Developer I** (Nov. 2017 to Nov. 2018)

Performed as Full-stack Web Application Developer using Spring, OpenShift, Java, and JavaScript. Collaborated with global coworkers and consultants remotely. Designed and implemented rebuilds for operational applications to control and monitor packages.

- Enhanced package controls by reworking an internal application
- Created and employed improved DevOps processes.
- Earned recognition from leadership and promotion.

ISO Developers, Winthrop, MA, 2016

## **Software Developer Co-Op**

Used Ionic Platform, HTML, AngularJS, and CSS to develop cross-platform mobile applications. Coded as part of a team using version control systems including Git. Increased knowledge of Firebase.

- Introduced product ideas using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to present to customers.
- Delivered completed full products to clients.

Applied Geographics, Inc., Boston, MA, 2016

#### **Network Administrator Co-Op**

Supported the website infrastructure updating and providing maintenance as required. Coordinated analytic reporting ensuring increased activity. Collaborated with a cross-functional team.

- Boosted wireless security with a RADIUS server for the 802.1X wireless network.
- Built positive team relationships to encourage cooperation.

# **Selected Projects**

#### Music Map, musicmap.lafronz.com

Created a Visualization of a Spotify user's library using D3, NodeJS, and Spotify's web API for users to view library items.

# Battleship Prototype, github.com/lafronzt/battleship

Constructed Battleship board game into a 1-player game in Assembly Language as part of a collaborative team of three.